<metadata xml:lang="en"><Esri><CreaDate>20170501</CreaDate><CreaTime>10391600</CreaTime><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce><ModDate>20170501</ModDate><ModTime>14561700</ModTime><scaleRange><minScale>150000000</minScale><maxScale>5000</maxScale></scaleRange><ArcGISProfile>ItemDescription</ArcGISProfile></Esri><tool name="ProcessGeogridFile" displayname="Process GEOGRID File" toolboxalias="" xmlns=""><arcToolboxHelpPath>c:\program files (x86)\arcgis\desktop10.3\Help\gp</arcToolboxHelpPath><parameters><param name="in_nc" displayname="Input GEOGRID File" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="File" expression="in_nc"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN STYLE="font-size:12pt"&gt;This is the input WRF GEOGRID file in netCDF (&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN STYLE="font-style:italic;font-size:12pt"&gt;.nc&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN STYLE="font-size:12pt"&gt;) format. This file must contain dimensions ‘west_east’and ‘south_north’, as well as the gridded variables ‘HGT_M’and ‘LU_INDEX’, which is the grid of elevation values and a land use grid, both on the Mass (‘M’) grid. The ‘HGT_M’variable is the grid used to initiate all of the WRF-Hydro routing grids. The GEOGRID file is typically produced using the WRF Preprocessing System (WPS). &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="in_csv" displayname="Forecast Points (CSV)" type="Optional" direction="Input" datatype="File" expression="{in_csv}"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN STYLE="font-size:12pt"&gt;This optional parameter requires a Comma-Separated Values (CSV; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN STYLE="font-style:italic;font-size:12pt"&gt;.csv&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN STYLE="font-size:12pt"&gt;) formatted file of gage locations in latitude/longitude coordinates (WGS84). This ASCII file should contain a 1 row header with gage location information on subsequent rows. The CSV file must contain a longitude field named ‘LON’and a latitude field named ‘LAT’as well as an ID field named ‘FID’in order to be read, and no header names are allowed to contain spaces or special characters. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="basin_mask" displayname="Mask CHANNELGRID variable to forecast basins?" type="Optional" direction="Input" datatype="Boolean" expression="{basin_mask}"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P STYLE="text-align:Justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN STYLE="font-size:12pt"&gt;This optional boolean (TRUE/FALSE) parameter asks the user whether or not to mask the output ‘CHANNELGRID’grid to the basins delineated based on the provided Forecast Points CSV file. The option is only available if a CSV file is provided in the ‘Forecast Points (CSV)’parameter. If TRUE (Checked), the derived gauged basins will be used to mask the channels in the ‘CHANNELGRID’grid. The resulting ‘CHANNELGRID’grid will contain values of 0 for channels inside a gaged basin, values of -1 for channels outside of gaged basins, and -9999 for all other areas. Masking out unwanted channels can result in a significant computational savings because routing is not performed on channels with -1 grid values.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="RB_routing" displayname="Create reach-based routing (RouteLink) files?" type="Optional" direction="Input" datatype="Boolean" expression="{RB_routing}"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN STYLE="font-size:12pt"&gt;This optional boolean (TRUE/FALSE) ‘Create reach-based routing (RouteLink) files?’parameter will produce additional output files that facilitate reach-based routing in WRF-Hydro. All channel elements will be vectorized and channel attributes and topology are summarized in the Route_Link.nc output file. Additional files created by this option include a ‘LINKID’variable in the ‘FullDom’file that gives a grid of the channels with values corresponding to the ‘link’variable in the Route_Link.nc file and a streams.shp line shapefile for plotting the streams in a GIS. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="Lake_routing" displayname="Create lake parameter (LAKEPARM) file?" type="Optional" direction="Input" datatype="Boolean" expression="{Lake_routing}"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P STYLE="text-align:Justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN STYLE="font-size:12pt"&gt;The optional Boolean (TRUE/FALSE) ‘Create lake parameter (LAKEPARM) file?’parameter will produce additional output files that facilitate the addition of reservoirs in WRF-Hydro. If TRUE (checked), the ‘Reservoirs Shapefile or Feature Class’and ‘ID field (INTEGER) for identifying lakes’parameters will become active and a polygon shapefile will be required and a fieldname may also be provided. Any integer type field may be selected from the input shapefile or feature class, or this parameter may be left blank. If left blank, a new ID will be created using a 1-n range of integer values and the outputs will reflect these new IDs. If a fieldname is provided, the outputs will reflect the values in this field.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="in_reservoirs" displayname="Reservoirs Shapefile or Feature Class" type="Optional" direction="Input" datatype="Feature Class" expression="{in_reservoirs}"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P STYLE="text-align:Justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN STYLE="font-size:12pt"&gt;The input reservoirs polygon feature class to be resolved on the routing grid.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="in_IDfield" displayname="ID field (Integer) for identifying lakes" type="Optional" direction="Input" datatype="String" expression="{in_IDfield}"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN STYLE="font-size:12pt"&gt;The integer field representing the unique ID of each reservoir feature in the input reservoirs feature class&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="in_raster" displayname="Input Elevation Raster" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="Raster Dataset" expression="in_raster"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN STYLE="font-size:12pt"&gt;This required ‘Input Elevation Raster’ parameter allows the user to provide a high-resolution digital elevation model (DEM) from which to derive the output layers. This grid must be an ArcGIS supported raster or mosaic dataset format, have the coordinate system defined, and cover the entire extent of the input GEOGRID domain. The test cases included with the download package have a DEM stored in a GeoTIFF format. Additionally, the terrain processing will very likely only be successful if the input DEM has been hydrologically processed to ensure continuous flow paths. Note: The vertical units must be in meters above sea level (m). &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="cellsize" displayname="Regridding (nest) Factor" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="Long" expression="cellsize"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P STYLE="text-align:Justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN STYLE="font-size:12pt"&gt;The required ‘Regridding (nest) Factor’parameter allows the user to set the output cell size for the derived datasets based on a relationship to the cell size in the GEOGRID file. The output high-resolution grids must be able to nest perfectly within the coarse GEOGRID resolution, and so the GEOGRID grid resolution will be divided by the regridding factor. Several examples are given in Table 3for a 1000m input GEOGRID resolution.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="threshold" displayname="Number of routing grid cells to define stream" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="Long" expression="threshold"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN STYLE="font-size:12pt"&gt;The required ‘Number of routing grid cells to define stream’parameter is the number of contributing cells from the routing grid used to initiate a stream segment. The number of contributing cells is given by the ‘flowacc’flow accumulation grid. Smaller thresholds will yield higher drainage density in the resulting channel network (‘CHANNELGRID’). &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="ovroughrtfac_val" displayname="OVROUGHRTFAC Value" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="Any value" expression="ovroughrtfac_val"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P STYLE="text-align:Justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN STYLE="font-size:12pt"&gt;‘OVROUGHRTFAC'. The default value for this grid is 1.0. Any valid number will be taken and the resulting ‘ovroughrtfac’variable will be a constant-value grid with that value. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="retdeprtfac_val" displayname="RETDEPRTFAC Value" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="Any value" expression="retdeprtfac_val"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN STYLE="font-size:12pt"&gt;‘RETDEPRTFAC’. The default value for this grid is 1.0. Any valid number will be taken and the resulting ‘retdeprtfac’ variable will be a constant-value grid with that value. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="out_zip" displayname="Output ZIP File" type="Required" direction="Output" datatype="File" expression="out_zip"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P STYLE="text-align:Justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN STYLE="font-size:12pt"&gt;This required parameter is the directory and filename (&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN STYLE="font-style:italic;font-size:12pt"&gt;.zip&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN STYLE="font-size:12pt"&gt;) of the output from the tool. This can be set to any location and filename that you choose, as long as you have read/write access to this location. The output format will be a ZIP archive containing compressed versions of all output files. Be sure to include the .zip file extension.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param></parameters></tool><dataIdInfo><idCitation><resTitle>Process GEOGRID File</resTitle></idCitation></dataIdInfo><distInfo><distributor><distorFormat><formatName>ArcToolbox Tool</formatName></distorFormat></distributor></distInfo><mdHrLv><ScopeCd value="005"/></mdHrLv></metadata>
